Camera, start.
Blow it up!
Did you enjoy "Return of Ultraman: MAT Arrow 1 Takeoff Order"?
Have a look at how it was shot in this making of special.
First, MAT Gyro.
What do you think the cockpit is made of?
Actually almost completely out of paper.
That's why it is being carried carefully so as to not break it.
It's tough.
While shooting they were careful not to break it with their acting too.
As you can see, the flying MAT Arrow was shot in a very unhealthy manner.
Look!
You got the eyes?
Yep.
It'll go out of focus!
That cockpit was also not made for the whole body, with the feet sticking outside.
You'd never imagine that, considering how cool it was in the film.
Shit, a barrier?
Come on!
Damnit, not enough energy!
Ejecting the battery pack.
The command room was filmed during the heat of summer but there is only one cooling device.
It was made without any breaks, day and night, by doing construction inside a reserved factory floor.
All of the command room is handmade: ceiling, walls, and floor.
Cardboard boxes and others are brought in to complete it.
Captain.
The nuclear weapons, at least stop the nuclear weapons.
(Rehearsal in the finished Command Room)
There might still be survivors in Hiratsune City.
Orders are to retreat, there will be no change.
But commander... please stop.
What can't you do?
Easy cuts, including rehearsals, were repeated over and over.
To the back of the table?
Tough job, give it up
Then let's try going up til here and then running swiftly.
Having to shoot late at night and sleepy is quite tough.
But they did play around like this during rehearsals.
You won’t avenge your countrymen?
Are you even human?
This brought the light to an end.
The nuclear weapons, at least stop the nuclear weapons.
There might still be survivors in Hiratsune City.
Ibuki might still be-
Captain, please stop.
Whoa, Hayakawa, what are you doing?
Isn’t it obvious! I’m taking us out of level 4.
Hayakawa, stop!
Won't you stop?
Let me go.
Bastard!
Guys, don’t you understand what you’re doing?
Let go!
Stop this, Hayakawa!
This is our chance to avenge Ibuki!
But!
You won’t avenge your countrymen? Are you even human?
Confine him to his quarters. And keep an eye on him.
Roger!
How's it going?
Under preparation.
Ah, I see.
What about this one here?
And just like that, the filming with this set was finished in 3 days.
Time to dismantle.
The command room which took a week to be made was dismantled in just 2 hours.
The miniatures were assembled in different sizes.
Compare them with the size of actual people.
The small tools for the open set were also made on the go.
The kaiju was also completed with many passes, all while bearing with the smell.
Strong response.
Finally, the location shoot.
The place is Yonago in Tottori prefecture, the foot of Mt. Daisen.
Went for a swim today, but it was paid.
Same here.
Raise your hands.
I hate that sound.
Preparing the film set.
When preparations are done,
shooting begins.
The smoke is being produced by a firework called a smoke ball.
Start.
Until OK is reached, it is repeated non-stop.
Okay.
Bug Jewel also takes a rest.
Filming also happened during the night.
It's raining.
When the rain stops, filming resumes.
Wait, wait.
I won't roll.
Roll it.
Yeah.
Oh, there's a car.
Shooting fireworks or gunpowder can only be done once.
No room for failure.
Shooting.
How well did it go?
I’m hit!
Ibuki!
Have a look at Ultraman's clothing.
All of the spare smoke balls caught fire!
Nevertheless, the filming continued this way.
This is no good.
No good.
Mistakes were made too.
But it went well most of the time.
Ready... Start!
Finally, the climax.
When they tried to film Bug Jewel in the end...
This time, it snowed.
Quite often unlucky.
Well then, let's redo it.
Sorry.
Camera, start.
Okay.
Somehow it was a success.
Great Japan for ya.
Shooting on location is finished.
Time to go back.
Back to Osaka.
6 months actually passed since production started in the summer.
It was March of the next year when the 80-man crew returned from Yonego to Osaka, and completed Ultraman.